# Carl Johnell - CV

Date of BirthWebsitecarljohnell.com10th of January 1993Emailcjohnell@gmail.com

#### Summary

CS MSc student at Chalmers. Previously worked as a software developer for 2.5 years, after having completed a BSc in Software Engineering at BTH. I am experienced in: high- and low-level programming, client- and server-side, as well as the complete software development process.

#### **Education**

**MSc in Computer Science**, Chalmers University of Technology September 2018 - Present, Gothenburg, SE

**Courses in Mathematics**, Lund University *January 2018 - June 2018*, Lund, SE

**BSc in Software Engineering**, Blekinge Institute of Technology September 2012 - June 2015, Karlskrona, SE

## **Work Experience**

Software Developer, Compuverde

August 2015 - January 2018, Karlskrona, SE

Designed, implemented & improved several features in the Software Defined Storage (SDS) product. Main development was in C++; various test and utility scripts were in Python. I learned a lot about storage, virtualization, multitude of different networking protocols, multithreading, server programming, and more.

### Some of my contributions:

- Worked on the implementation of several different networking protocols: Kerberos, LDAP, NFS, NNTP, NTLM, RPCSEC\_GSS.
- Implemented an Amazon S3 server compatible with a subset of the official API.
- Created a driver for OpenStack Block Storage (Cinder).
- Developed a REST API for easier management and administration of a storage cluster.
- Extended the system's networking capabilities to allow for more adaptable configuration options.
  This made it easier for customers to integrate the system to their existing networking environment.
- Improved the main build script which reduced the time of incremental debug builds by 90%.

## Summer Internship, Ericsson

June 2015 - August 2015, Karlskrona, SE

In a group, developed an internal tool that's used to compose and visualize different use cases supported by Ericsson Charging System. The tool was a web application that was installed and run locally on a user's computer, and I was responsible for the Java server implementation and many of the technical decisions.

## Software Developer, Malvacom

June 2014 - December 2014, Karlskrona, SE

Part-time work during studies. Android development and Python web development.

## Skills

**Programming languages**: C, C++, Go, Java, Javascript, Python **Technologies**: Docker, Git, HTML5/CSS3, Linux/Unix, LLVM, SQL

## **Personal Projects**

Dingo, github.com/cjo5/dingo

Compiler for a C-like programming language with easy interop from and to C. Statically typed and compiles to LLVM. Support for basic C features, defer, slices & modules. Written in Go.